MONTSERRAT MIRANDA

IT PROJECTS

Currently working on

Au Pair Pairing | Jan 2022- present

Development of a CRUD web application from scratch using the MERN stack (MongoDB, Express.js, React.js and Node.js). The purpose of the app is to feature an interactive map where users can search and add learning content linked to specific places in the world.

Communication Platforms | Jan 2022- present

Full implementation of SDLC to bring 3 main online communication workflows into one software landscape. Including research and analysis of different off-the-shelf software alternatives and creation of procurement plan for acquisition, tests for requirements validation and user manual with product delivery.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Au Pair

Cultural Care | July 2018 - current

- Creation and implementation of diverse educational strategies to boost development and a global citizen mindset on the kids and interest for technology.
- Monthly updating of schedule balancing active play, instruction and Au Pair hours available.
- Teaching Spanish and different cultures to 5 and 7yo on a daily basis.

Talent Acquisition Specialist

North American Production Sharing, Inc. | Feb 2017 - Mar 2018

 Recruitment, selection and hiring process of middle management positions for over 20 companies in the automotive industry in Mexico.

Talent Acquisition Coordinator

Danone de Mexico | Jan 2016 - Feb 2017

• Recruitment, selection and hiring process of interns, entry level and middle management positions.

VOLUNTEER WORK

AIESEC Mexico | Aug 2013 - Dec 2015

- As **President**, I directed a team of 10 people and oversaw the operations of an office with over 55 members, ranked top 1 national level in one of our 4 products by the end of the year.
- As VP of HR, I managed a team of 13 people. Implemented several tools to improve the experience of the members which eventually led us to won 1st place on the Annual National Awards Ceremony.

CONTACT

montserrat.mirandaperez@gmail.com 443-630-9097

in linkedin.com/in/mont-miranda
montserrat.miranda.github.io

github.com/montserratmiranda

Baltimore, MD

EDUCATION

Towson University

MS Applied Information Technology Graduate Certificates

- Internet Applications Development
- Information Systems Management Towson, MD | Expected in May 2022

University of Guanajuato

BBA Human Resources
Guanajuato, Mexico | Dec 2015

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- JavaScript ES6+
- Node.js
- Express.js
- MongoDB
- React.js
- HTML5
- CSS
- MS Project

LANGUAGES

Spanish

Native/Bilingual



English

Native/Bilingual



ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- Valid Passport
- Visa F1, looking for OPT